So we now want to set up our project
imdi projemizi kurmak istiyoruz ve her
and first of all I'll set up the project structure I want to work with.
eyden nce birlikte almak istediim proje yapsn kuracam.
Now I won't recreate the exact structure of create react app but a fairly similar one, I'll create a source
imdi tepki reaksiyonu oluturma uygulamasnn tam yapsn yeniden oluturmayacam ama olduka benzer bir yap, kk klasrmzde bir kaynak
folder in our root folder and in that source folder, I'll add my index.html file
klasr oluturacam ve bu kaynak klasrnde dizinimi ekleyeceim. html dosyas bu yzden
so this single page which gets served in the end. In that file we can run
sonuta sunulan tek sayfa. Bu dosyada html ve grsel
html and in visual studio code,
stdyo kodu altrabiliriz, imdi
I now get this snippet I can use by choosing this HTML5 snippet and hitting enter,
bu HTML5 paracn seip enter tuuna basarak kullanabileceim bu parac alyorum,
I get a HTML5 boilerplate out of the box,
kutudan bir HTML5 boilerplate alyorum,
you can of course write this manually.
elbette bunu elle yazabilirsiniz.
So this should be the starting html file we work with,
Bu, birlikte altmz balang html dosyas olmal,
if you got any imports from CDNs of fonts or styles you can add that in the head section, the scripts
eer yaz tipi veya stilleri CDN'lerinden herhangi bir ithalat aldysanz, ba ksmnda bunu ekleyebilirsiniz, i
and any other imports generated by the workflow will be injected into this file automatically though, we'll
ak tarafndan oluturulan komut dosyalar ve dier tm aktarmlar otomatik olarak bu dosyaya enjekte
add a configuration which does this to our set up.
edilecektir. Bunu kurulumumuza yapan bir yaplandrma ekleyeceiz.
With that I'll now add a div to this body which should get a specific ID root,
Bununla birlikte, belirli bir kimlik kk almas gereken bu bedene bir div ekleyeceim, bu
this will be the div where we'll later mount our react application to.
daha sonra reaksiyon uygulamamz monte edeceimiz div olacaktr.
With that the index.html file is done,
Bu endeksle. html dosyas tamamland, imdi
now let's set up the other parts of this project. In the source folder,
bu projenin dier blmlerini ayarlayalm. Kaynak klasrde, kullandmz
I want to have the assets folder where we could store images or anything like that we use,
gibi bir resim veya herhangi bir ey
I also want to set up a components folder and a container folder
depolayabileceimiz varlk klasrne sahip olmak istiyorum. Ayrca, bir
so basically the same setup I used in my other project in the project
bileen klasrn ve bir kapsayc klasrn kurmak
in this course. Now I also want to create a react application, for that I'll create an index.js file
istiyorum. Bu derste proje. imdi de bir tepki uygulamas oluturmak istiyorum, bunun iin bir indeks oluturacam. js dosyas,
in the source folder and the index.css file which I want to use for some global styling,
kaynak klasrde ve dizinde. Baz global stiller iin kullanmak istediim css dosyas,
so this will be imported in the index.js file, there I'll import that index.css file
bu dizin iinde ie aktarlacak. js dosyas, o dizini alacam. Css dosyas daha sonra
where I then can set up the body rules to remove the margin of the body, any padding we might have
vcudun kenar boluunu kaldrabilmek iin vcut kurallarn ayarlayabildiimiz herhangi bir dolgu
and also to set the font family, let's simply set it to sans-serif here.
ve ayrca yaz tipi ailesini ayarlayalm, hadi bunu sans-serif'e ayarlayalm.
So this is a basic set up there,
Yani buradaki temel bir
now I also want to add an app.js file which should be my root component and then so that we
kurulum, imdi de bir uygulama eklemek istiyorum. Benim root bileenim olmas gereken js dosyas
can really see that all of that works,
ve tm bunlarn gerekten altn
I want to set up a basic react project which isn't super amazing but which uses routing and lazy loading
grebilmemiz iin sper artc olmayan ama ynlendirme ve tembel ykleme kullanan temel bir
so that we can see if that works and which just simulates a lot of features we might use in a typical
tepki projesi kurmak istiyorum. Bu, tipik bir tepki uygulamasnda kullanabileceimiz pek ok zellii simle
react application,
eden ve bunun
for example it should also incorporate an image. Now I'll set up this demo react project in the next lecture,
da bir grnt iermesi gerektii anlamna gelir. imdi bir sonraki derste bu demo tepki
you can also skip this if you just want to see the workflow set up, I'll provide the finished project
projesini kuracam, sadece i akn grmek istiyorsanz bunu atlayabilirsiniz, son dersin sonunda
at the end of last lecture or attached to next lecture
bitmi projeyi veya sonraki derse ekleyeceim ama
but if you want to see it, I'll walk through it in full detail so that we set up a react app here from scratch
Bunu grmek isterseniz, tm detaylaryla birlikte yryeceim, bylece burada bir tepki uygulamas kuralm. Bir
Let's do that in the next lecture.
sonraki derste bunu yapalm.